# VINCE SCACCHITTI

16 Seymour Road – Unit 2H East Granby, CT 06026 VScacchitti24@gmail.com

LinkedIn: Vincent Scacchitti GitHub: VScacchitti

Mobile: (860) 913-5775

#### **SUMMARY**

With over 12 years experience working with client engagement in the health and fitness industry. I have successfully played the various roles both specific to my business and to buisness overall these include: personal training, management, coaching, business ownership, member sales, business to business sales, and staff training and development. I am known for my positive outlook, attention to detail, and ability to create excellent working relationships with clients, and co-workers. I have the ability to adapt to changing environments and situations, and I look forward to applying many of these abilities and skills as a back-end or full-stack web-developer.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Langauges: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQUERY, DOM, Node.JS, APIs

Applications: jQuery, BootStrap, Moment.Js

## **PROJECTS**

HomeWork Helper | https://github.com/VScacchitti/HomeworkHelper | https://vscacchitti.github.io/HomeworkHelper/

- This project was designed to help students adapt to the world of virtual learning. It was designed to help students stay organized and engaged in the virtual classroom.
- My core responsibilities were working with our API's, and coding the JavaScript functionality of the draw, English and math pages.
- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Document Object Model, multiple APIs.

## QuizAPP | https://github.com/VScacchitti/QuizApp | https://vscacchitti.github.io/QuizApp/

- This quiz is timed, begins on a start button, the quiz lets a user know if they are correct or incorrect by showing red or green on the selected answer. The top 5 quiz scores are saved onto a High Scores page where the user can enter their initials or name, and their score will be saved it to local storage if it is one of the top 5.
- I did all development on this application.
- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Document Object Model (DOM).

### WeatherDash | https://github.com/VScacchitti/WeatherDashboard | https://vscacchitti.github.io/WeatherDashboard/

- WeatheDash allows you to search for current and 5-day extended forecast conditions for any city just by searching! This appuses an open weather API to pull current conditions such as temperature, humidity and wind speed!
- I did all the development for this application.
- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Document Object Model (DOM), jQuery, OpenWeather API

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Fortitude Fitness, East Granby, CT

March 2014- Jun 2020

**Owner** - Connecticut based Training, heatlth and fitness business with full scale facility located in East Hartford until business was converted to an in-home company with a final transition to remote in 2020 before closing in June. **Facility:** 

- Oversaw process of facility construction
- Oversaw staff of 2 trainers and two front desk workers
- Staff Scheduleing and Payroll
- Staff Training
- Managing montly growth and sales goals.

### **In-Home:**

- Oversaw the transition from a physical facility to training in-home.
- Trainer would bring equipment to client home for scheduled training,

#### Remote:

- Final transition to all online training due to Covid-19 pandemic.
- Offered online classes and programming.

### Landwarrior Crossfit, Suffield CT

# September 2019- June 2020

Coach- Coach- Instructing and leading members in the daily implementation of scheduled workout and accessory work Member Engagement- Work to engage member on social media with the creation of various work-out activities, games and remote workouts during the pandemic.

## Crossfit Berlin, Berlin, CT

**August 2019- June 2020** 

Coach- Instructing and leading members in the daily implementation of scheduled workout and accessry work.

### VPS Associates. LLC -

January 2006 - Present

Connecticut based, Global Management Consulting Business. Primary responsibilities include: Data Entry, Systems Support and Market Research.

# Anytime Fitness, Glastonbury, CT

September 2012-March 2014

*Fitness Director*- Responsibilities included:

- Overseeing a staff of 3 trainers to help with monlthy goal setting to support and maintain each trainers personal training engagement with clients
- Achieve Monthly Goals to increase overall training revenue
- Schedule new member orientations and assessments with trainers
- Manage payroll

## Personal Trainer

August 2012-March 2014

- Create and implement exercise programs designed specifically for a client
- Programs include weight loss, increased muscle mass, and increased sports performance
- Maintained and tracked client progress on a monthly basis

## **EDUCATION**

- BootCamp Certificate, 2021, UCONN Full Stack Coding Bootcamp
- Graduate Coursework- Counseling, University of St. Joseph, West Hartford, CT
- Diploma Professional Fitness Training, 2012, Brandford Hall Career Institute, Windsor, CT, GPA: 4.0
- Bachelor of Arts, 2005, Merrimack College, North Andover, MA; Major: History/Minor: Secondary Education

References available upon request